TIANA HO'OLANA HUSTED

Eugene, OR 97401 | (971)404-1043 | tiana.husted@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/tiana-husted-395057163/ | GitHub: https://github.com/thusted |

Portfolio: https://thusted.github.io

SUMMARY

Web developer with a background in tech-based art and a passion for learning new technologies. Extensive experience with custom interface design for interactive art installations, utilizing microprocessors and sensors. Through the creation of immersive art environments, I have developed a keen sense for anticipating different ways users interact with various interfaces. I integrate that knowledge into my work and am committed to approaching any project with innovation and creativity.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, JQuery, HTML, CSS, Max/MSP, Arduino IDE (C, C++, Java), Processing (Java)

Applications: Bootstrap, NodeJS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars.js, ReactJS

PROJECTS

Alertify

https://github.com/thusted/Alertify | https://alertifynow.herokuapp.com/

Provides users with additional security in case of emergency. Send an alert with Alerify mobile tracker if immediate rescue is needed.

- Wrote back end code that utilized geolocation and texting API; Integrated code into front end design; Implemented database interaction through MvSOL
- Directed team of 4 developers to successfully meet deadlines and achieve project goals
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, NodeJS, MySQL, Sequelize, Passport, BCrypt, Quick Easy SMS API

AdVOTEcate

https://github.com/thusted/adVOTEcate | https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=7E06hS wm4g

AdVOTEcate is your advocate for any voting needs! This app shows users how to register to vote, where the nearest polls are, and provides information on how to vote by mail.

- Wrote back end code using Google Maps and Google Civic Information API
- Coordinated a team of 4 developers to collaboratively strategize front end design; achieved project goals and deadlines
- Tools/Languages Used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Express, Axios, Node, MongoDB, Material UI, Google Maps API, Passport, and Google Civic Information API

Bezier Data Visualization

https://github.com/thusted/Bezier-Data-Visualization | https://youtu.be/Pd81FM694fs

Bezier Data Visualization uses bezier curves to plot data, using government CSV files from 2017. This sketch allows users to see a visual representation of how often (on a scale of percentage) the members of the Senate and House vote in line with Trump's position.

- Designed images/animation and wrote code
- Tools/Languages Used: Processing (Java)

EXPERIENCE

Independent Website Consultant and Designer, Eugene, OR

January 2021-Present

- Build and maintain relationships with clients
- Work collaboratively to develop artistic vision for website designs
- Facilitate weekly check-ins to ensure product is up to client standards
- Familiarize and train clients to use tools that help them maintain their websites

Department Director, House of Strange Rituals LLC, Eugene, OR

September 2018-Present

- Co-founded all-female Eugene-based interactive art collective
- Manage the collective's Sound and Interactive Art Department
- Develop and construct interactive elements in large-scale art exhibitions
- Train and delegate tasks to team members
- Engineer circuits, design custom software, program Arduino microprocessors, and produce original sound for art pieces
- Co-directed *The Dollhouse* art installation and exhibited at Burning Man in 2019
- Co-wrote and awarded competitive Black Rock City Honoraria Grant for \$20,000
- Produced events and fundraised \$18,000

Audio Technician, Velvet Thunder Sound Systems, *Eugene*, *OR*

July 2018-March 2020

- Operated specialized sound equipment for events at McDonald theatre
- Planned and executed equipment set-up in collaboration with touring performers and crews
- Utilized excellent problem-solving abilities in fast-paced technical environment
- Demonstrated adaptability during unpredictable events and strong attention to detail

Monitor Engineer, High Sierra Music Festival, Quincy, CA

July 2018 and 2019

- Constructed and deconstructed stages and sound systems
- Engineered sound for 7 performances a day for 4 consecutive days at 1,000-person shows
- Adapted stage design and sound engineering on a moment's notice between sets
- Devised work plans to execute tasks on an extremely tight timeline

EDUCATION

The Complete Android Oreo Developer Course: Udemy, Online

Currently enrolled

• A 37.5-hour course focused on Android App Development with Android 8.0 Oreo. Building real apps including Twitter, Instagram, and Super Mario Run.

Certificate in Full Stack Web Development: University of Oregon, *Portland, OR*

April 2020-October 2020

• A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Bachelor of Science: Music Technology: University of Oregon, Eugene, OR

September 2016-December 2018

• A 4-year program focused on electronic composition, sound design, and musical interface design.

Associate's Degree: General Studies/Music: Lane Community College, *Eugene, OR* September 2013-June 2016

• A 2-year Associate's degree with an extended focus on music theory and composition, music technology, and audio engineering.